[Music]
jaffa cakes
a classic
biscuit
or
i don't know are they biscuits are they
cake i mean the cakes in the title and
the sponge underneath is
technically
a cake because it goes hard when it goes
off
cookies biscuits go soft when they go
off cakes go hard when they go off so
who knows what it is
if you don't have jaffa cakes where you
are they're amazing soft kind of sponge
base with a orange
jaffa or
you know
jaffa orange i assume
um
sugary soft circle
tops covered in chocolate they used to
do i think they do now some raspberry
ones some apple ones blah blah blah
various different flavors but all just
used to be orange
actually they did do an old chocolate
one
years ago years and years and years ago
they were the best ones i've ever had
still orange flavored but all covered in
chocolate and i think they had chocolate
sponge but i can't remember if you
remember that all chocolate chocolate
cakes let me know in the comments
comments whether they had the chocolate
sponge or not
i saw these in the shops the other day
and thought i'd have a go at making a
jaffa cake ice cream so here we are
let's get started and see where we end
up
as per usual we're going to start with
our milk add in our sugars we've got
sugar and dextrose in here and then
we're going to add in our milk powder if
you want to add a stabilizer to this add
it to your sugar before you put it in a
pan make sure it's well combined
once all that's completely mixed in add
in some cocoa powder i used caliber
cocoa powder here it's 22 to 24 fat
the small amount we're adding here
smaller than normal that's for sure will
give us a milk chocolate as you can see
here result
once that's up to temperature you can
turn the heat off and then add in some
chocolate now if you're watching this
and we haven't done the next episode of
our chocolate series we'll discuss this
combination chocolate ice cream in that
episode
and or have done depending on what time
of the year is
anyway once that's ready take it off the
heat add it into your container and here
we're going to add in our cream
afterwards to cocoa the chocolate is
well combined
it's nicely emulsified we can then add
in our cream and put that in the fridge
[Music]
whilst that's chilling down in the
fridge we're going to make our fudge and
what we're going to do here is a
chocolate orange fudge so in the pan
start your corn syrup and your milk add
in your coconut oil at that stage and
warm it up nicely
i've added the sugar in here you don't
have to wait for the coconut oil to melt
if you don't want to
once that's all fully melted down as you
can see here oh look a tiny little lump
add in your cocoa powder get that really
well mixed and bring that up to a
rolling boil get it really nice and hot
once that's been boiling for about 30
seconds turn the heat off and add in
your chocolate the chocolate will bring
the temperature down and it will make a
really nice glossy smooth chocolate
fudge
once that's cooled down a little bit
more add in your orange extract now
we've used nielsen macy here it's really
nice and tastes identical to the jaffa
cake flavor which is really handy
take that off the heat put it in a
container and just let it cool down to
room temperature before you put it in
the fridge if you put it in the fridge
it will stiffen up a little bit it won't
go hard but it will stiffen up
when your ice cream has chilled in the
fridge give it a nice little mix just to
make sure it's ready to go pop it in
your ice cream machine for churning
smells great this chocolate ice cream
once your ice cream's churning you can
take some of your chopper cakes and chop
them up into whatever size you like i've
just done a random kind of one
centimeter squares or squarish shapes
here
and
when your ice cream is ready you can
simply start loading up the tub now
loading up tub is just layering it in
your ice cream and then your fudge
one by one and then finally top with
your chopped jaffa cake pieces now put
the lid on that and put it in the
freezer for 20 minutes half an hour or
so whilst that's in the freezer take
your milk chocolate add a little bit of
coconut oil to it and melt that down
i've just melted this down in the
microwave nice and quick let it cool
down a little bit take your ice cream
out the freezer and then pour your milk
chocolate all over the top of your jaffa
cakes put it back in the freezer then
for a good few hours
[Music]
we've got our jaffa cake ice cream out
the freezer nice tub look jaffa cake
mirrors the kind of look of the actual
box itself
let's get some scooped up and in a bowl
i do love the chocolate tops i mean ben
and jerry's do them that's where i got
the idea to do them so you know just
pure out copying them
but
really nice it's it's theatrical
breaking through that chocolate top it's
theatrical it's nice it's it's i mean i
gave a tub of this to
where my wife works she took it into the
office and everyone loved just taking
the spoons and diving in you know so it
was a real nice element to this kind of
ice cream that a lot don't have and ben
and joe's is often a little bit
disappointing let's be fair so
i can smell the orange coming out it's
really really good looking forward to
trying this one let's dig in and see
what it tastes like
[Music]
oh man that is good
that's good
that chocolate orange fudge
something i did in this i didn't mention
in the video earlier
was i took some of those orange pieces
from the actual jaffa cake themselves
chopped them up into little cubes added
it into that fudge just before loading
it into the tub it just gives a little
bit more texture
a little bit more bite to the fudge but
the fudge tastes identical to jaffa
cakes so you've got the milk chocolate
you got the chocolate orange fudge you
got that
chocolate ice cream oh this is so good
i'm definitely making this one again
if you like jaffa cakes or have no idea
what they are try this recipe it's a
really really good
flavor impersonation in ice cream form
so i hope you enjoyed this video don't
forget to like and subscribe and we'll
see you next week
[Music]